# **Damon Rocha**

Sherman, Texas 75092 | 903-818-3759 | dmarcr1997@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/dmr4414/| https://dev.to/dmarcr1997 | https://dmr-portfolio-site.herokuapp.com/home

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript-based programming with a background in C++ and Python. Detailed Math, Calculus, and Physics background centered around electronics and science. Possess strong skills in team-building and project management that help engineering and technical companies produce optimized results. Has the ability and desire to learn any and every skill.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, C++, Python, Computer Science, Computer Assembly, and x86 Assembly language

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

GalaxyScout - https://github.com/dmarcr1997/GalaxyScout | https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Emud4GU9GgQ&t=1s or http://galaxyscout.herokuapp.com/

Ruby on Rails Application for browsing and creating pictures from space

- Regulated data using Active Record associations and rails server
- Implemented Nested Routes to show model associations
- Created index scope to sort data by comments and creator
- Utilized PostgreSql database

Assignment Hog - https://github.com/dmarcr1997/SinatraProj AssignmentHog | https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g3J1jAKRQeo

Sinatra based online classroom for students to communicate and track assignments

- Included shotgun server to open site in browser
- Used SQLite database to handle data
- Applied sessions and has secure password to control site access
- Stored user ID as foreign key in message table to allow users to create and send private messages to other users

SyntheticAi - https://github.com/dmarcr1997/synthetic-ai | https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S-0TE-VRugl or https://dmarcr1997.github.io/Synthetic-ai-production/

Javascript front-end with Rails API back-end AI application

- Administered Brain.js to allow use of AI in browser
- Parsed PostgreSql data to JSON serializer to communicate data from Rails Api to JavaScript Code
- Created JavaScript classes to separate concerns between AI, Users, and overall webpage
- Implemented ES6 syntax to allow cleaner code and better context

## **EXPERIENCE**

**UPS** Sherman, TX 07/2018 - 03/2019 Seasonal Package Loader

- Streamlined customers parcels arrival by creation of system to organize packages
- Produced better results for drivers by partitioning package line distribution and helping co-workers

Kohl's Sherman, TX 04/2017 - 07/2018

Home and Kids Supervisor

- Created better shopping experience for customers by overseeing clean-up, updates, and management of Home and
- Strategically directed monthly projects with a team to reorganize Home and Kids area to match the monthly merchandise plan given-for a larger store.

## **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** Online 01/2020 - 06/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Denison, TX

**Grayson County College** Associates of Science General Studies 12/2017

Associates of Science Computer Science 12/2019

08/2015-12/2019